<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.zoutmax.FifineControlDeck</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>fifine Control Deck</name>
  <summary>Control a Stream Dock style macro keypad</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      A native Linux control application for the fifine Control Deck — a
      Mirabox / Hotspot "Stream Dock" style macro keypad with per-key LCDs
      (USB 3142:0060).
    </p>
    <p>
      Draw icons and labels on the keys and bind them to actions: launch apps,
      send hotkeys, type text, media and volume control, run scripts,
      brightness, page and profile switching, folders and multi-step macros —
      via a PyQt6 configuration GUI.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">fifine-control-deck.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://zoutmax.github.io/FifineControlDeck/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/ZoutMax/FifineControlDeck/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/ZoutMax/FifineControlDeck</url>

  <developer id="io.github.zoutmax">
    <name>Daniel Houtmann</name>
  </developer>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ZoutMax/FifineControlDeck/main/assets/store/screenshot-01-overview.png</image>
      <caption>Actions catalog, the live key grid with system-monitor keys, and the key-settings panel</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ZoutMax/FifineControlDeck/main/assets/store/screenshot-02-editor.png</image>
      <caption>Editing a key: icon, colours, label and the assigned action</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.12.4" date="2026-07-23">
      <description>
        <p>Five fixes from a whole-codebase architecture audit: real device write errors are detected, reordering pages no longer crashes on a deck race, the headless service saves deck-driven brightness/profile, a GPU-key NVML leak, and password secrets are removed from the keyring when a key is cleared</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.3" date="2026-07-23">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes a folder being stranded when its page is deleted while the deck navigated into it during the confirmation</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.2" date="2026-07-23">
      <description>
        <p>Three audits of the action engine, the configuration model and the system-monitor sampler: confirmations before deleting a page or a folder key, config backups that no longer overwrite each other, apps launched from a key fixed on the AppImage and snap, monitor keys that report a dead deck, and several corrected readouts. Supersedes the withdrawn 0.12.0 and 0.12.1.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.3" date="2026-07-22">
      <description>
        <p>Adds an AppImage so the app can be installed on distributions without apt, such as Fedora, Arch, openSUSE and SteamOS. It is a single file that brings its own Python and Qt. The application itself is unchanged from 0.11.2.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.2" date="2026-07-22">
      <description>
        <p>Memory no longer climbs as you switch pages: repainting a key that already shows the same picture is skipped, which over a soak of 600 switches cut growth from 82 MB to 7 MB. Pages with more than six animated keys stop re-decoding them on every switch, a password inside a multi-action is no longer exported without warning, and the app now tells you when it cannot read your configuration instead of silently starting fresh.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.1" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>Animated keys no longer stall the window the first time they appear. Decoding an animation now happens on its own thread, so the key shows its static face immediately and starts animating a moment later, instead of freezing the interface for about a quarter of a second per animated key.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.0" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>Clears the audit backlog, mostly in the device layer. A quick unplug and replug no longer leaves the deck dead while the app still says it is connected; installing the udev rule now takes effect without a restart; a deck that is plugged in but unusable is reported honestly instead of as connected; animated keys no longer re-decode on every page switch; unplugging during quit can no longer crash the app; and typing keys, password keys and config export now say what they are doing instead of failing silently.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.2" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes two shutdown defects in the device layer. Pulling the cable while an animated key is playing could free the USB handle underneath a thread still writing to it, killing the app instead of disconnecting cleanly. Quitting no longer waits out the keep-alive timer: across repeated tests, shutdown went from between 2.9 and 30 seconds, sometimes failing outright, to a consistent 2.8 to 3.1 seconds.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.1" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes two regressions from 0.10.0: a config with no profiles was treated as corrupt and its brightness and other settings reset, and the window failed to open with no visible message when the background service already held the deck.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.0" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>An idle app no longer burns a CPU core: a redundant USB rescan that
        cost about 7% of a core continuously is throttled, so laptops get the
        battery life back. A hand-edited config file that parses but has the
        wrong shape is now preserved instead of being silently replaced and
        overwritten, and a config from a newer version is backed up before it
        is downgraded. The headless service and the GUI can no longer both
        drive the deck and fire every key press twice. The key grid no longer
        drifts apart into empty bands on a tall window, deselecting a key
        clears both the settings panel and the key highlight, dropping an
        action can no longer land on the wrong page, and the brightness slider
        follows changes made from the deck.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2026-07-20">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.9.0</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.2" date="2026-07-20">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.8.2</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.1" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Dark-mode color dialog fix and synchronous --quit</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Press-and-hold key actions, one-click GPU temperature, clock formats</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Monitor keys round 2 (GPU load, temperatures, clock), gauge legibility</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.2" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Icon picks stick for good (provenance tracking) plus a 25-fix editor audit and legacy-ydotool typing fix</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.1" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Library icon picker fix, plus font fallback</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>System monitor keys: live CPU, RAM, VRAM, network and disk readouts on key LCDs as numbers, gauges or graphs</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.8" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Security and data-safety release: udev uaccess fix, passwords off argv, folder and keyring data-loss fixes, enforced single instance</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.7" date="2026-07-13">
      <description>
        <p>Classic snap that drives the deck, with a one-click button to enable device access.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.6" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed a Qt/Wayland startup warning by setting the app identity before QApplication.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.5" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Restored netlink USB hotplug by recommending python3-pyudev.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.2" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Folders, multi-action editor, production hardening; amd64 and arm64.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
